# Tara Boroushaki

tarab@mit.edu | tara-boroushaki.com

# RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests lie in sensing and mobile technologies with applications in wireless networking, wireless sensing, cyber-physical systems (including robotics), and cyber-human systems. I develop algorithms and build systems for multi-modal sensing to connect, perceive, and interact with the environment in novel ways to enable more efficient, robust, and capable mobile, cyber-physical, and cyber-human systems.

#### EDUCATION

Massachusetts Institute of Technology	MA, USA
Doctor of Philosophy, Perception & Sensing Technologies Advisor: Prof. Fadel Adib	June 2021 – present
Massachusetts Institute of Technology	MA, USA
Master of Sciences, Digital Communication and Multimedia	Sep. 2019-June 2021
Thesis: Robotic Grasping of Fully-Occluded Objects using RF Perception	
Sharif University of Technology	Tehran, Iran
B.Sc. in Electrical Engineering	June 2019
Awards & Honors	
Marconi Society Young Scholar Award	2024
• N2WOMEN: Rising Stars in Networking & Communications	2024
• Microsoft Research PhD Fellow	2022-2024
• IEEE RFID '23 Best Paper Award	2023
• Meta Research PhD Fellowship (declined in favor of Microsoft fellowship)	2022
• RFusion in "103 Ways MIT is Making the World Better"	2022
• ACM SenSys '21 Best Paper Award Finalist	2021
• Neekeyfard Fund Award	2022
Duri igationg	

# Publications

- SeaScan: An Energy-Efficient Underwater Camera for Wireless 3D Color Imaging Nazish Naeem, Jack Rademacher, Ritik Patnaik, Tara Boroushaki, and Fadel Adib, ACM MobiCom, Nov 2024
- 2. Reinforcement Learning for RFID Localization Weitung Chen, **Tara Boroushaki**, and Fadel Adib IEEE RFID, June 2024, **Best Paper Finalist**
- 3. Demo: Real-time X-Ray Vision via Augmented Reality with RF Sensing **Tara Boroushaki**, Maisy Lam, Weitung Chen, Laura Dodds, Aline Eid, and Fadel Adib *ACM SIGCOMM*, September 2023
- 4. Exploiting Synergies between AR and RFIDs for Item Localization and Retrieval **Tara Boroushaki**, Maisy Lam, Weitung Chen, Laura Dodds, Aline Eid, and Fadel Adib *IEEE RFID*, June 2023, **Best Paper Award**

5. Augmenting Augmented Reality with Non-Line-of-Sight Perception Tara Boroushaki, Maisy Lam, Laura Dodds, Aline Eid, and Fadel Adib

USENIX NSDI, April 2023

6. FuseBot: Mechanical Search of Rigid and Deformable Objects via Multi-Modal Perception

**Tara Boroushaki**, Laura Dodds, Nazish Naeem, and Fadel Adib *Autonomous Robots*, *September 2023* 

7. FuseBot: RF-Visual Mechanical Search

**Tara Boroushaki**, Laura Dodds, Nazish Naeem, and Fadel Adib Robotics: Science and Systems (RSS), June 2022

8. RFusion: Robotic Grasping via RF-Visual Sensing and Learning

**Tara Boroushaki**, Isaac Perper, Mergen Nachin, Alberto Rodriguez, and Fadel Adib, *ACM SenSys, November 2021*, **Best Paper Finalist** 

9. Robotic Grasping of Fully Occluded Objects using RF Perception

**Tara Boroushaki**, Junshan Leng, Ian Clester, Alberto Rodriguez, and Fadel Adib, *IEEE ICRA*, May 2021

#### PATENTS

- 1. Tara Boroushaki, Fadel Adib, and Junshan Leng, "System and Method for Location Determination and Robot Control," US Patent Application No. 17530603, Filed November 2021.
- 2. Tara Boroushaki, Isaac Perper, and Fadel Adib, "Methods and Apparatus for Robotic Grasping via RF-Visual Sensing and Learning," US Patent Application No. 17819685, Filed August 2022.
- 3. Tara Boroushaki, Maisy Lam, Laura Dodds, Aline Eid, and Fadel Adib, "Augmenting Augmented Reality with non-line-of-sight Perception," US Provisional Patent Application No. 63408240, Filed September 2022.

# MENTORING EXPERIENCE

I have had the opportunity to mentor many students at MIT:

- Graduate students: Laura Dodds, Maisy Lam, Nazish Naeem, Weitung Chen, Isaac Perper
- Undergraduate students: Toya Takahashi, Natalie Tang, Ian Limarta, Monica Liu, Suleman Thaniana

### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

- Teaching Assistant, How To Wirelessly Sense Almost Anything, MIT, Fall 2022
- Guest Lecturer, Computer Networks, MIT, Fall 2023
- Teaching Assistant, Principles of Electrical Engineering, Sharif University of Technology, Fall 2016 & 2017

#### Academic Service

- $\bullet$  Co-Chair of ACM S  $^3$  Workshop in Mobile Computing and Networking Conference, 2023
- Shadow PC member for the ACM Conference on Embedded Networked Sensor Systems (SenSys), 2022
- Reviewer for IEEE Transactions on Mobile Computing and the ACM Transactions on Internet of Things
- External Reviewer for the ACM Mobicom, SIGCOMM, Mobisys, and the USENIX NSDI
- Reviewer for the IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L), and ICRA
- Chair of Automation: Sensors and Grasping Session in ICRA'21

Research Intern

June 2022 – Sep 2022

Microsoft Research, Redmond, WA, USA

• Worked on next generation Mixed Reality Headsets in the Microsoft Networking Research Group and Mixed Reality with Dr. Jouya Jadidian and Dr. Bodhi Priyantha.

Research Assistant July 2018 – Jan. 2019

Computer Vision and Geometry Group, ETH Zurich, Switzerland

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming: C/C++, Python (including TensorFlow, Pytorch), MATLAB, R, Java
- Robotics: ROS, Simulation (e.g. CoppeliaSim, Gazebo, and Pybullet), Universal Robots UR5e, Robotiq 2f-85 gripper
- Sensing Systems:
  - Radars and Software-Defined Radios: TI 77GHz Radar (AWR1642), Infineon's 24GHz radar (BGT24MTR12), Socionext 60GHz Radar (SC1220AT2), BladeRF, Ettus USRP N210
  - Vision Sensors: Microsoft HoloLens 2, Intel RealSense D415, Himax (hm01b0) image sensor
- Hardware and Circuit Design: Ansys Electronics, AVR Microcontrollers, Altium Designer, HSPICE

# INVITED TALKS

• RF-Visual Perception with Applications to Mobile Sensing, Robotics, & Augmented Reality

University of Wisconsin-Madison, May 2024

Harvard University, April 2024

Yale University, April 2024

UIUC, March 2024

University of Maryland, College Park, March 2024

• Giving Humans and Robots X-Ray Vision

TEDx MIT, April 2023, [Link]

• Super-Human Perception with Radio Frequencies

MAS Research Talks, MIT, May 2022

• Robotic Grasping via RF-Visual Sensing and Learning

Harvard (SEAS), December 2021

• Superhuman Robot Senses: Using Radio Frequencies to See Hidden Objects

MIT Horizon, June 2021

#### Selected Press Coverage

- X-AR: MIT News, Boston Globe Media, Communications of ACM, 7 NEWS WHDH, Popular Science, etc.
- FuseBot: MIT News[Front Page], Vision System Design, TechCrunch, etc.
- RFusion: MIT News [Front Page], BBC, World Economic Forum, Daily Mail, VoA News Russian, etc.
- RF-Grasp: The Wall Street Journal, MIT News, ACM TechNews, IEEE Spectrum, Mashable, etc.